According to the theories of human social development.
[AI] 根据人类社会发展理论。
we're now living through the fourth great epoch of technological advancement.
[AI] 我们现在正经历着技术进步的第四个伟大时代。
the Information Age.
[AI] 信息时代。
Connectivity through digital technology is a modern miracle.
[AI] 通过数字技术实现互联互通是一个现代奇迹。
We can say it has broken down barriers of time and space which separate people.
[AI] 我们可以说，它打破了分隔人们的时间和空间的障碍。
and it's created a condition for an age where information. ideas can be shared freely.
[AI] 这为信息时代创造了条件。思想可以自由分享。
But are these great accomplishments in digital technology really the endgame in terms of what can be achieved?
[AI] 但就可以实现的目标而言，这些数字技术方面的伟大成就真的是终结吗？
I don't think so.
[AI] 我不这么认为。
and today I'd like to share with you
[AI] 今天我想和大家分享
how I believe digital technology can take us to even greater heights.
[AI] 我如何相信数字技术可以把我们带到更高的高度。
I'm a surgeon by profession.
[AI] 我的职业是外科医生。
and as I stand here today talking to all of you.
[AI] 今天我站在这里和你们大家谈话。
five billion people around the world lack access to safe surgical care.
[AI] 全世界50亿人无法获得安全的外科治疗。
Five billion people.
[AI] 50亿人。
That's 70 percent of the world's population.
[AI] 这是世界人口的70%。
who according to the WHO's Lancet Commission
[AI] 根据世界卫生组织柳叶刀委员会
can't even access simple surgical procedures as and when they need them.
[AI] 他们甚至不能在需要的时候进行简单的外科手术。
Let's zoom in on Sierra Leone.
[AI] 让我们放大塞拉利昂。
a country of six million people.
[AI] 一个有六百万人口的国家。
where a recent study showed that there are only 10 qualified surgeons.
[AI] 最近的一项研究表明只有10名合格的外科医生。
That's one surgeon for every 600.000 people.
[AI] 每60万人中就有一名外科医生。
The numbers are staggering.
[AI] 数字惊人。
and we don't even need to look that far.
[AI] 我们甚至不需要看那么远。
If we look around us here in the US.
[AI] 如果我们看看美国的周围。
a recent study reported that we need an extra 100.000 surgeons by 2030
[AI] 最近的一项研究报告称，到2030年，我们需要额外的10万名外科医生
to just keep up with the demand for routine surgical procedures.
[AI] 只是为了满足常规外科手术的需求。
At the rate that we're going. we won't be meeting those numbers.
[AI] 以我们前进的速度。我们不会满足这些数字。
As a surgeon. this is a global issue that bothers me.
[AI] 作为一名外科医生。这是一个困扰我的全球性问题。
It bothers me a lot.
[AI] 这让我很烦恼。
because I've seen firsthand
[AI] 因为我亲眼见过
how lack of access to safe and affordable healthcare
[AI] 如何获得安全和负担得起的医疗保健
can blight the lives of ordinary people.
[AI] 会影响普通人的生活。
If you're a patient that needs an operation
[AI] 如果你是一个需要手术的病人
and there isn't a surgeon available.
[AI] 而且也没有外科医生。
you're left with some really difficult choices:
[AI] 你将面临一些非常困难的选择：
to wait. to travel.
[AI] 等待。旅行。
or not to have an operation at all.
[AI] 或者根本不动手术。
So what's the answer?
[AI] 那么答案是什么？
Well. part of you are carrying some of that solution with you today:
[AI] 好今天，你身上带着一些解决方案：
a smartphone. a tablet. a computer.
[AI] 智能手机。平板电脑。一台计算机。
Because for me.
[AI] 因为对我来说。
digital communications technology has the power to do so much more
[AI] 数字通信技术有能力做更多的事情
than just to allow us to shop online.
[AI] 而不仅仅是让我们在网上购物。
to connect through social media platforms and to stay up to date.
[AI] 通过社交媒体平台进行连接并保持最新。
It has the power to help us solve some of the key issues that we face.
[AI] 它有能力帮助我们解决我们面临的一些关键问题。
like lack of access to vital surgical services.
[AI] 比如缺少重要的外科服务。
And today I'd like to share with you
[AI] 今天我想和大家分享
an example of how I think we can make that possible.
[AI] 这是一个我认为我们可以做到这一点的例子。
The history of surgery is filled with breakthroughs
[AI] 外科手术的历史充满了突破
in how science and technology was able to help the surgeons of the day
[AI] 科学技术是如何帮助当时的外科医生的
face their greatest challenges.
[AI] 面对他们最大的挑战。
If we go back several hundred years.
[AI] 如果我们追溯到几百年前。
an understanding of microbiology
[AI] 对微生物学的理解
led to the development of antiseptic techniques.
[AI] 导致了防腐技术的发展。
which played a big role in making sure patients were able to stay alive postsurgery.
[AI] 在确保患者术后存活方面发挥了重要作用。
Fast-forward a few hundred years
[AI] 快进几百年
and we developed keyhole or arthroscopic surgery.
[AI] 我们开发了锁孔或关节镜手术。
which combines video technology and precision instruments to make surgery less invasive.
[AI] 它结合了视频技术和精密仪器，使得手术的侵入性更小。
And more recently. a lot of you will be aware of robotic surgery.
[AI] 最近。你们中的很多人都知道机器人手术。
and what robotics brings to surgery is much like modern automated machinery.
[AI] 机器人技术给外科手术带来的好处很像现代自动化机器。
ultraprecision.
[AI] 超精密。
the ability to carry out procedures at the tiniest scales
[AI] 以最小规模执行程序的能力
with a degree of accuracy that even surpasses the human hand.
[AI] 准确度甚至超过了人手。
But robotic surgery also introduced something else to surgery:
[AI] 但是机器人手术也给手术带来了一些其他的东西：
the idea that a surgeon
[AI] 一个外科医生
doesn't actually have to be standing at the patient's bedside to deliver care.
[AI] 实际上不必站在患者床边进行护理。
that he could be looking at a screen
[AI] 他可能在看屏幕
and instructing a robot through a computer.
[AI] 并通过计算机指导机器人。
We call this remote surgery.
[AI] 我们称之为远程手术。
It is incumbent on us
[AI] 这是我们义不容辞的责任
to find solutions that solve these answers in a cost-effective and scalable way.
[AI] 以经济高效和可扩展的方式找到解决这些问题的解决方案。
so that everyone. no matter where they are in the world.
[AI] 让大家都知道。不管他们在世界的什么地方。
can have these problems addressed.
[AI] 我们可以解决这些问题。
So what if I told you that you didn't really need a million-dollar robot to provide remote surgery?
[AI] 那么，如果我告诉你，你真的不需要一个百万美元的机器人来提供远程手术呢？
That all you needed was a phone. a tablet. or a computer.
[AI] 你只需要一部电话。平板电脑。或者一台电脑。
an internet connection.
[AI] 互联网连接。
a confident colleague on the ground
[AI] 实地的一位自信的同事
and one magic ingredient:
[AI] 还有一个神奇的成分：
an augmented reality collaboration software.
[AI] 增强现实协作软件。
Using this augmented reality collaboration software.
[AI] 使用这个增强现实协作软件。
an expert surgeon can now virtually transport himself into any clinical setting
[AI] 一位专家外科医生现在几乎可以将自己转移到任何临床环境中
simply by using his phone or tablet or computer.
[AI] 只需使用他的手机、平板电脑或电脑。
and he can visually and practically interact in an operation from start to finish.
[AI] 他可以在手术中从头到尾进行视觉和实际的互动。
guiding and mentoring a local doctor through the procedure step by step.
[AI] 一步一步地指导和指导当地医生。
Well. enough of me telling you about it.
[AI] 好我已经告诉你够多了。
I'd now like to show you.
[AI] 我现在想给你看。
We're now going to go live to Dr. Marc Tompkins.
[AI] 我们现在要向马克·汤普金斯博士直播。
an orthopedic surgeon at the University of Minnesota.
[AI] 明尼苏达大学的整形外科医生。
He's going to perform an arthroscopic surgery for us.
[AI] 他将为我们做关节镜手术。
a keyhole surgery of the knee.
[AI] 膝盖的锁孔手术。
and I'd like to disclose
[AI] 我想透露一下
that this patient has consented to having their operation streamed.
[AI] 该患者已同意进行手术。
I'd also like to point out that in the interest of time.
[AI] 我还想指出，为了时间的利益。
we're just going to go through the first steps.
[AI] 我们将只进行第一步。
marking up the patient
[AI] 给病人打分数
and just identifying a few key anatomical landmarks.
[AI] 只需确定几个关键的解剖标志。
Hello. Dr. Tompkins. can you hear me?
[AI] 你好汤普金斯博士。你能听到我说话吗？
Dr. Mark Tompkins: Good morning. Nadine.
[AI] 马克·汤普金斯博士：早上好。纳丁。
Nadine Hachach-Haram: Everyone from TED says hello.
[AI] 纳丁·哈查赫·哈拉姆：TED的每个人都打招呼。
Audience: Hi.
[AI] 观众：嗨。
NHH: Alright. Dr. Tompkins. let's get started.
[AI] NHH：好的。汤普金斯博士。让我们开始吧。
So let's start with our incisions and where we're going to make these.
[AI] 让我们从切口开始，从哪里开始。
on either side of the patellar tendon.
[AI] 在髌腱的两侧。
So if you can make your incisions there and there.
[AI] 所以如果你能在那里切割的话。
that should hopefully get us into the knee.
[AI] 这很有可能让我们的膝盖受伤。
MT: All right. I'm going in.
[AI] MT：好的。我要进去了。
NHH: Great.
[AI] NHH：太好了。
So we're just getting inside the joint now.
[AI] 所以我们现在就要进监狱了。
So why don't we go around and have a quick look at the meniscus.
[AI] 那么我们为什么不四处看看半月板呢。
MT: Perfect.
[AI] 太好了。
NHH: Great. so we can see there's a small tear there on the meniscus.
[AI] NHH：太好了。我们可以看到半月板上有一个小裂口。
but otherwise it looks alright.
[AI] 但除此之外，它看起来还不错。
And if you turn and head to this direction.
[AI] 如果你转向这个方向。
follow my finger.
[AI] 跟着我的手指走。
let's have a quick look at the ACL and the PCL.
[AI] 让我们快速查看一下ACL和PCL。
That's your ACL there. that looks quite healthy.
[AI] 那是你的ACL。看起来很健康。
no problems there.
[AI] 没问题。
So we've just identified that small meniscus tear there.
[AI] 我们刚刚确认了那个小半月板撕裂。
but otherwise the fluid around the joint looks OK as well.
[AI] 但除此之外，关节周围的液体看起来也不错。
All right. thank you very much. Dr. Tompkins. Thank you for your time.
[AI] 好吧非常感谢你。汤普金斯博士。谢谢你抽出时间。
I'll let you continue.
[AI] 我让你继续。
Have a good day. Bye.
[AI] 祝您今天过得愉快。再见
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
So I hope through this simple demonstration
[AI] 所以我希望通过这个简单的演示
I was able to illustrate to you just how powerful this technology can be.
[AI] 我能够向你们说明这项技术有多么强大。
And I'd like to point out that I wasn't using any special equipment.
[AI] 我想指出的是，我没有使用任何特殊设备。
just my laptop and a really simple webcam.
[AI] 只有我的笔记本电脑和一个非常简单的网络摄像头。
We're so used to using digital technology
[AI] 我们已经习惯了使用数字技术
to communicate through voice and text and video.
[AI] 通过语音、文字和视频进行交流。
but augmented reality can do something so much deeper.
[AI] 但增强现实技术可以做得更深。
It allows two people to virtually interact
[AI] 它允许两个人进行虚拟交互
in a way that mimics how they would collaborate in person.
[AI] 以一种模仿他们亲自合作的方式。
Being able to show someone what you want to do. to illustrate and demonstrate and gesture.
[AI] 能够让别人知道你想做什么。说明、演示和做手势。
is so much more powerful than just telling them.
[AI] 比仅仅告诉他们要强大得多。
And it can make for such a great learning tool.
[AI] 它可以成为一个非常好的学习工具。
because we learn better through direct experience.
[AI] 因为我们通过直接经验学习得更好。
So how is this making a difference around the world?
[AI] 那么，这对全世界有什么影响呢？
Well. back in my teaching hospital.
[AI] 好回到我的教学医院。
we've been using this to support local district general hospitals
[AI] 我们一直在用它来支持当地的地区综合医院
and providing skin cancer surgery and trauma treatment.
[AI] 提供皮肤癌手术和创伤治疗。
Now. patients can access care at a local level.
[AI] 现在患者可以在当地获得护理。
This reduces their travel time. improves their access.
[AI] 这减少了他们的旅行时间。改善他们的访问。
and saves money.
[AI] 而且省钱。
We've even started seeing its use in wound care management with nurses
[AI] 我们甚至开始看到它在护士伤口护理管理中的应用
and in outpatient management.
[AI] 在门诊管理方面。
Most recently. and quite exciting.
[AI] 最近。非常令人兴奋。
it was used in supporting a surgeon through a cancer removal of a kidney.
[AI] 它被用于支持外科医生切除肾脏肿瘤。
And I'd like to just share with you a very quick video here.
[AI] 我想在这里和大家分享一个非常快速的视频。
I apologize for some of the gruesome views.
[AI] 我为一些令人毛骨悚然的观点道歉。
(Video) Doctor 1: OK. Show me again.
[AI] （视频）医生1：好的。再给我看看。
Doctor 2: If you see here.
[AI] 医生2：如果你看到这里。
that's the upper part. the most outer part of your tumor.
[AI] 那是上半部分。肿瘤最外层的部分。
Doctor 1: Yes.
[AI] 医生1：是的。
Doctor 2: So it's three centimeters deep.
[AI] 医生2：那么它有三厘米深。
so this should be three centimeters.
[AI] 这应该是三厘米。
Doctor 1: Yes. yes.
[AI] 医生1：是的。对
Doctor 2: OK. so you need to get a 3.5 margin.
[AI] 医生2：好的。所以你需要获得3.5的利润。
Doctor 1: I'm going to show you anyway
[AI] 医生1：不管怎样，我都要给你看
and tell me what you think about it.
[AI] 告诉我你是怎么想的。
NHH: We're also seeing the use of this technology at a global scale.
[AI] NHH：我们也看到了这项技术在全球范围内的应用。
and one of the most heartwarming stories I can recall
[AI] 我能回忆起的最温馨的故事之一
is from the town of Trujillo in the north of Lima in Peru.
[AI] 来自秘鲁利马北部的特鲁希略镇。
where this technology was used to support the provision of cleft lip and palate surgery to children.
[AI] 该技术用于支持为儿童提供唇腭裂手术。
children from poor backgrounds who didn't have access to health insurance.
[AI] 没有医疗保险的贫困儿童。
And in this town. there was a hospital with one surgeon
[AI] 在这个镇上。有一家医院有一名外科医生
working hard to provide this care.
[AI] 努力提供这种护理。
Dr. Soraya.
[AI] 索拉亚博士。
Now. Dr. Soraya was struggling under the sheer demand of her local population.
[AI] 现在索拉亚博士在当地居民的强烈需求下苦苦挣扎。
as well as the fact that she wasn't specifically trained in this procedure.
[AI] 以及她没有接受过这方面的专门培训。
And so. with the help of a charity.
[AI] 等等。在慈善机构的帮助下。
we were able to connect her with a cleft surgeon in California.
[AI] 我们能把她和加利福尼亚的一位唇裂外科医生联系起来。
and using this technology. he was able to guide her and her colleagues
[AI] 使用这项技术。他能够指导她和她的同事
through the procedure step by step.
[AI] 一步一步地通过这个程序。
guiding them. training them and teaching them.
[AI] 引导他们。训练他们，教他们。
Within a few months.
[AI] 几个月之内。
they were able to perform 30 percent more operations
[AI] 他们能够执行30%以上的操作
with less and less complications.
[AI] 并发症越来越少。
And now Dr. Soraya and her team can perform these operations
[AI] 现在索拉亚博士和她的团队可以进行这些手术了
independently. competently and confidently.
[AI] 独立地。干练而自信。
And I remember one quote from a mother who said.
[AI] 我还记得一位母亲说过的一句话。
"This technology gave my daughter her smile."
[AI] “这项技术让我女儿笑了。”
For me. this is the real power of this technology.
[AI] 为了我。这就是这项技术的真正力量。
The beauty is that it breaks boundaries.
[AI] 美在于它打破了界限。
It transcends all technological difficulties.
[AI] 它超越了所有技术难题。
It connects people. It democratizes access.
[AI] 它把人们联系起来。它使访问民主化。
Wi-Fi and mobile technology are growing rapidly.
[AI] Wi-Fi和移动技术发展迅速。
and they should play a role in boosting surgical provision.
[AI] 他们应该在促进手术供应方面发挥作用。
We've even seen it used in conflict zones where there's considerable risk
[AI] 我们甚至看到它在有相当大风险的冲突地区使用
in getting specialist surgeons to certain locations.
[AI] 把专业外科医生送到特定地点。
In a world where there are more mobile devices than there are human beings.
[AI] 在一个移动设备比人类多的世界里。
it truly has a global reach.
[AI] 它确实具有全球影响力。
Of course. we've still got a long way
[AI] 当然我们还有很长的路要走
before we can solve the problem of getting surgery to five billion people.
[AI] 在我们能解决给50亿人做手术之前。
and unfortunately.
[AI] 不幸的是。
some people still don't have access to internet.
[AI] 有些人仍然无法上网。
But things are rapidly moving in the right direction.
[AI] 但事情正在朝着正确的方向迅速发展。
The potential for change is there.
[AI] 改变的潜力是存在的。
My team and I are growing our global footprint.
[AI] 我和我的团队正在扩大我们的全球足迹。
and we're starting to see the potential of this technology.
[AI] 我们开始看到这项技术的潜力。
Through digital technology.
[AI] 通过数字技术。
through simple. everyday devices that we take for granted.
[AI] 通过简单。我们认为理所当然的日常设备。
through devices of the future.
[AI] 通过未来的设备。
we can really do miraculous things.
[AI] 我们真的可以做奇迹。
Thank you.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）